<Document> 
# DUPE Station Server Rules 
[bold]Welcome to DUPE Station![/bold]

DUPE Station is a Medium Roleplay (MRP) Space Station 14 server. Roleplay over Gameplay. Admins may choose to ignore potential rule breaks if it is beneficial or high-effort roleplay. Admins may also intervene to guide rounds toward higher RP standards or to protect players.

[color=yellow]This is an 18+ server[/color]. Any users suspected of being underage will be banned until they are of age.


Core Rules

[textlink="0. Admins have final say." link="RuleAdmins"]

[textlink="1. Don't be a dick." link="RuleDontBeADick"]

[textlink="2. Don't metagame nor powergame." link="RuleMetagame"]

[textlink="3. Keep IC and OOC separate." link="RuleICKOCK"]

[textlink="4. Don't Self-antag." link="RuleSelfantag"]

[textlink="5. No Bigotry/Harassment." link="RuleBigotry"]

[textlink="6. No Explicit/Shock Content." link="RuleNSFW"]

[textlink="7. This is an English server, speak English." link="RuleEnglish"]

[textlink="8. Don't Hack or abuse Exploits, including Macros." link="RuleHacker"]

[textlink="9. Don't be excessively incompetent." link="RuleSkillIssue"]

[textlink="10. No Shuttlebombing or EORG." link="RuleEORG"]

Core Guidelines

[color=#a4885c]01.[/color] [color=#a4885c]The[/color] [color=#ffd700]Golden[/color] [color=#a4885c]Rule.[/color]
Admins may exercise discretion with rules as they see fit. Rule-lawyering or line-skirting will result in removal. Admins are accountable internally for the use of this discretion.

[color=#ff0000]ZERO TOLERANCE RULES[/color]

[color=#a4885c]02.[/color] Absolutely no hate speech, slurs, bigotry, racism, specism (demeaning characters in-game due to race), sexism, disability-related harassment, or anything even remotely similar. (PERMABAN)

[color=#a4885c]03.[/color] Erotic Roleplay (ERP) and sexual content are forbidden.

Explicit sexual actions or descriptions are not allowed.

Rape, sexual assault, coercion, pregnancy, fertility, or breeding-related RP is strictly forbidden.

Sexual humor, innuendo, and crude jokes are allowed if non-graphic, non-directed, and not round-driving.

Romantic relationships are allowed strictly for background RP; dating-focused RP is prohibited.
(VIOLATIONS = PERMABAN)

[color=#a4885c]04.[/color] Metacommunication is forbidden. Do not share IC information via external channels (Discord, voice chat, etc.). (PERMABAN)

[color=#a4885c]05.[/color] Ban evasion results in automatic appeal-only permanent bans. Job-ban evasion is also appeal-only permanent.

[color=#ff0000]GENERAL ETIQUETTE[/color]

[color=#a4885c]06.[/color] English only IC and OOC. Character accents may be roleplayed (ex: Italian accent), but English is the primary language.

[color=#a4885c]07.[/color] No exploits, external programs, or scripts to gain advantage, automate gameplay, or disrupt the server. AFK evasion macros are prohibited. Lag/crash attempts = appeal-only ban.

[color=#a4885c]08.[/color] No multi-keying (using multiple SS14 accounts). All accounts involved will be banned.

[color=#a4885c]09.[/color] Respect the admin help system. Do not spam, flood, or ignore it. Hostility toward admins = removal.

[color=#ff0000]IN-GAME & ROLEPLAY RULES[/color]

[color=#a4885c]10.[/color] Names must be realistic, first & last name required. Leeway for Clowns, Mimes, and non-humans.

No parody or famous person names.

No phonetic joke names.

[color=#a4885c]11.[/color] Medium Roleplay (MRP) standards expected:

No text-speak or emoticons IC.

No OOC references.

Genuine effort to play your role.

[color=#a4885c]12.[/color] Don’t be a dick.

Arrival areas and shuttle docks are off-limits for hostile activity.

Don’t intentionally ruin other players’ experiences.

Round is not over until end-round summary.

Antagonists have leeway but cannot degrade overall RP or prolong rounds unnecessarily.

[color=#a4885c]13.[/color] No metagrudging (harassment across rounds).

[color=#a4885c]14.[/color] No metagaming. Use only knowledge your character would have.

Ghost roles do not remember past lives unless explicitly stated.

[color=#a4885c]15.[/color] Escalation rules must be followed. Use common sense.

Defend yourself as needed.

Security may use less-lethal force for arrests.

Don’t leave people to die; assist medically if possible.

Department strikes, riots, revolutions, cults, etc., require admin permission.

[color=#a4885c]16.[/color] Do not immediately ghost/suicide from your role if you do not receive antagonist or head roles without notifying command/admins.

[color=#a4885c]17.[/color] No powergaming.

Do not acquire equipment or weapons unrelated to your job without IC reason.

Do not manufacture weapons or poisons without immediate need.

Do not pre-emptively prepare for end-of-round scenarios.

[color=#a4885c]18.[/color] Self-antagging is forbidden.

Clowns and Mimes must entertain, not disrupt.

Violating this rule may result in arrest or punishment.

[color=#ff0000]SECURITY & COMMAND RULES[/color]

[color=#a4885c]19.[/color] Command/Security are held to a higher standard.

Competence in role expected.

Heads must manage priorities and fill understaffed areas.

Captain must have functional knowledge of all major departments and emergencies.

Do not abandon station duties or your role.

[color=#a4885c]20.[/color] Security/Command should prefer non-lethal arrests unless justified:

Immediate danger, lethal threat, inability to detain, extreme station risk.

Lethal force must be justified and accountable.

[color=#a4885c]21.[/color] Protect detainees:

Prevent unnecessary deaths.

Brig times ≤10 mins unless permabriggable.

Confiscate dangerous items as needed.

Clone detainees unless legally executed or strong antagonist evidence.

Borging allowed with consent.

[color=#ff0000]SILICON RULES[/color]

[color=#a4885c]22.[/color] Silicons must follow laws:

Law priority is mandatory.

Interpretations must remain consistent.

Posing danger may result in disablement/destruction.

Borgs remember past lives but obey laws.

[color=#00ff00]SANDBOX SPECIFIC RULES[/color]

[color=#0066ff]Blueshield Officer Rules[/color]

Protect Station Heads and Central Command VIPs.

Higher standard of play expected.

Do not abandon duties or self-promote to Captain.

[color=#00ff00]Nanotrasen Representative Rules[/color]

Relay Central Command directives.

Guide Station Heads when needed.

Do not abuse all-access.

Held to same standard as command roles.

By accepting these rules, you consent to the DUPE Station server redialing you to other servers in our network.
</Document>